Hi, and welcome to the SQL Masterclass course, where you will learn how to manage your data and how
to perform analysis on your data using SQL.
My name is Abhishek and along with my co instructor Poco Raj, I will be leading you through this course
as instructors.
Our courses have been enrolled by over a million students worldwide.
We both hold engineering and MBA degrees and have previous work experience of data analytics and consulting
industry.
While doing our jobs, we realized that businesses today are moving from traditional intuition based
decision making to data driven decision making.
Therefore, the use of SQL is now no longer limited to developers or programmers.
Even business managers, analysts and marketing researchers need to learn this language.
We have designed this course for individuals who wish to build a career in these fields and learn a
skill from the basic to the advanced level.
If you put one hour a day regularly within two weeks, you will be able to fetch any kind of data and
analyze the data using SQL based commands.
We will start this course by setting up PostgreSQL and PKG admin in your system so that you can practice
side by side.
We have selected PostgreSQL because most big companies in the field of analytics are using PostgreSQL.
But do not worry.
Even if you are working on any other dialect such as my SQL or Microsoft SQL, almost all the queries
have similar syntax.
I will also discuss a case study in the beginning of the course to demonstrate how a skill is used to
answer business questions.
Then we will take our first steps into a school and learn how to create a database, create tables in
a database, and then add data into those tables.
Next, we will learn some fundamental commands of SQL, which will enable us to query that is, retrieve
the data from a database.
We often want the data to be processed and to contain some information.
For this, we will learn how to filter and sort the data so that we retrieve only relevant information
and that to in the order we like.
After that, we will learn how to group data and find out aggregate values such as sum and count.
Then we will cover some advanced and important topics such as joints, subcommittees, views and indexes.
Next, we cover in different sections the different types of functions such as string functions, mathematical
datetime, and window functions.
Apart from this, at the end of the course, we have included some best practices and performance tuning
techniques for storing and retrieving the data in the most efficient way.
Lastly, we have also added some 30 lectures covering some important topics which are often asked in
interviews so that you can track the interviews for the job that you always wished for.
The ideal student for this course is a fresh graduate looking for a job as an analyst or a programmer
or a working professional who wants to explore or expand their skill set.
There are no prerequisites for this course.
We will teach you everything from basic to advanced level.
We only ask that you do practical exercises side by side.
If you have any doubt or query throughout the course, you can post them in the discussion forum.
We will be solving all your doors, so feel free to have a look at the course description and we look
forward to seeing you inside.